Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- O.W.F. Co. (Oakland Waterfront Co.)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Southern Pacific Co. adements”. Right of way contracts or deeds and maps, 1913 - 1918. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - “Oakland W. & Co. - Voucher Record, Bound ledger in file., April 1906 - April 1915. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - “O.W.F. Bank Deposit Book, Crocker-Woolworth Wat'l. Bank”. Bank book in file., 1906-1922 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - “O.W.F. Co. Misc.”. Contracts for deeds (copies), correspondence, notations and memos, sketches of maps, maps, descriptions of land, financial sheets., Dates: 1870 - 1914. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - “O.W.F. - Misc. Contracts, Agreements, Lease Options. List of contents: 1st item includes maps, old handwritten deed - other material Chronological order., Aug. 23, 1893, 10/15/03 - 2/3/15. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - “O.W.F. Co. Misc. Deeds” quitclaim and otherwise, mortgages and release, list of contents: 1st item, items in order given on list., Dates range: 1899 - March 1916. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - “O.W.F. - Sessions, Reports ”. Two large maps: 1. Portion of Alameda Marsh land, 2. Entrance to the San Francisco Bay., 1915 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Dredging Operations”. First two items lists concents, contracts, applications, proposals, bonds., Dates Range: 1917 - 1921. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. - Oakland Harbor Dredging”. Reports, contracts, resolutions and ordinances granting certain rights to O.W.F. Co., maps, some correspondence, notations of figures, memos and sketches of maps., Dates: July 26, 1900 - Aug. 12, 1919. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - “Oakland W.F. Co. - Oakland Harbor Dredging - Map”., 1917 - 1918. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - “O.W.F. - United Engineering Works sale 1901”. List of contents, deeds and contracts, 1901 - 1916. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - “O.W.F. Co. Alaska Packers Assn. 1905 Sale”. List of contents, deeds, contracts, 1905 - 1917. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - “United ng. Works, 1913”. Proposed deed notations and memos., 5/1/13 - (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - P.I. Co. & O.W.F. Co. Deed to U.S. ”., 4/25/14 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Agreement W/S.F. Bridge Co. for Construction of Spillway 1917”. map., 12/22/17 - (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - “O.W.F. - Sale to Union Iron Works - Actual, Signed Contracts - 1917”. List of contents - first item, deeds, agreements, resolutions, map, 3/29/17 - 2/13/18. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Agreements with Union Iron Works ”. List of contents., 3/18/18 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - “O.W.F. Union Iron Works Sale - Correspondence”., 2/21/16 - 3/24/17. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Tract 30, Sale to Union Iron Works, Contract Drafts”. Deeds, contracts, options, right of way deeds, all, dated 1917. (Box 11, Folder 27)
- T.O.W.F. Co. (Oakland Water Front)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Tract 30 Sale to Union Iron Works - Working Papers”. Maps, 1916 - 1917. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Sale to Demerritt - 1917”. List of contents, Oct. 1917 - Dec. 1918. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Transfer to U.S. Shipping Board, Emergency Fleet Corporation - 1918”. List of contents, July - Sept. 1918. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Taxes on Land Deeded to U.S. Shipping Board, Emergency Fleet Corporation 1918”. Memoranda and correspondence re: taxes, certificate of redemption of real estate, land goes back to O.W.F. Co., Dates: 2/2/20 - 6/9/21. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Alameda Naval Base Site - 1920”. Copy of publication - Oakland Achievement - Vol. IV, No. 1, all articles on Naval Base., Nov. 1920. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - “Oakland W.F. Co. - Legal, Contra Costa Water Co. v. O.W.F. Co. (1909)”. Testimony and cross examination of consulting engineers re: depreciation in suit heard by U.S. Circuit Court, Nov. 1909. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - 1917 Levee Break Litigation Papers”. List of contents, dates 11/17/15 - 4/11/19. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - “Oakland W.F. Co. - Legal, Litigation Re: Levee Break During Dredging”. In Superior Court 1. Chas. Fitch and 2. Lee Beckley v. Standard American Dredging Co., both answered by O.W.F. Co. 3. O.W.F. Co. v. Standard American Dredging Co., notes on case, correspondence., 1/9/17 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Wilson v. Standard American Dredging (1/9/17 Levee Break), Files of Chickering & Gregory Attorneys for Defense”. Various cases, Wilson always plaintiff, copies of complaint & summons, court reports on developments of case, correspondence, 1/16/17 - 1/29/18. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - “Wilson v. Std. American Dredging, 1917, Transcript: 10/25/17, 10/29/17”. Examination of Alan S. Wilson (direct, cross - cross, re-direct, recross -, 10/24, 10/29). (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Wilson v. Std. American Dredging, 1917 - Transcript: 10/31/17, 11/1/17, 11/5/17”. Examination of witnesses, important witnesses - A.B. Southard, A.D. Wilson and A.S. Southard, J. Beaumont and A.B. Southard., 10/31 - 11/1 - 11/2 - (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Wilson v. Std. American Dredging, 1917 - Transcripts: ”. A.B. Southard, J. Beaumont, A.D. Wilson - all re-called (again)., 11/6/17, 11/7/17, 11/8/17 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - “O.W.F. Co. v. Std. Amer. Dredging 1917 - Transcripts: ”. Motion for non-suit on behalf of O.W.F. Co. - denied, end of defense., 11/12-11/17, 11/15/17, 11/19/17 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - “Leroy v. O.W.F. Co. - 1919”. In U.S. District Court, copy of summons and complaint, May 8, 1919. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - “O.W.F. Co. Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co. - Documents”. In Superior Court of Calif., file includes stipulations, notices, memoranda, supoena. Article in back re: Alameda vote on sewer bond issue., 1920 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co. - Van Fleet Correspondence”. Includes reports, charts, but predominantly correspondence and memoranda of attny for O.W.F. Co., Van Fleet, 10/6/19 - 8/8/21. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co. - Exhibits”. Maps, photographs, reports - agricultural and financial, municipal resolutions giving O.W.F.Co. permission to dredge., 1920 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - “Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co., 1921 - Transcripts: ”. Testimony of Angelo Ghiglione, among others., 1/17/21, 1/18/21, 1/19/21 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous
  - “Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co., 1921, Transcript: ”., 1/20/21, 2/9-10/21, 2/14-16/21 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - “Ghiglione v. O.W.F. Co., 1921 - Transcript: ”. J. Beaumont testimony., 2/16-17/21, 2/21/21 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Sessions v P.I. Co., 1920”. In Superior Court of Calif. George S. Sessions v. P.I. Co. and O.W.F. Co., court documents - notices, subpoenas, affadavits, 2/28/19 - 6/1/20. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - “O.W.F. Co. - Sessions v. P.I. Co. - Transcript: ”. Opening statements and testimony of Sessions and S.F.B. Morse, among others., 2/16/20 2/18/20 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - “Sessions v. P.I. Co., 1920 - Transcript: ”. Testimony of Sessions, among others., 2/19/20,-2/24/20 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - “O.W.F. Co. Sessions v. P.I. Co., 1920 - Transcripts: ”. 2/25 - deposition of J.W. Powell, 3/3 - court's instructions to jury., 2/25/20, 3/3/20 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - “Antioch Holding & Investment Co.”. Stock certificate of 81 shares owned by Ione Coal & Iron Co., 3/26/1912 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - “California and Oregon R.R., San Francisco and Marysvilles R.R.”. C. & O. R.R. Stock Certificate (Corp. organized two S.F. & M. R.R. Stock Certificates also Southern Pacific and P.I. Co. Correspondence, dated June 27, 1863 June 2, 1863), dated Aug. 19, 1858, Nov. & Dec. 1900. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - “Capay Valley Land Co. - Stock Cert(ificate), By-Laws, Decreasement of Stock”. value of each share deminished to 1/100 of worth., 5/8/1896 - 12/12/18 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - “Capay Valley Land Co. - Meeting Notices, 1907 - 1920 - Proxies”., 1/4/07 - 8/16/20. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - “Capay Valley Land Co. (?) - Land Sales Record Book ”., 1903-1908 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - “Capay Valley Land Co.”. Financial reports, memos, correspondence, notations, receipts, bills, contracts, corporate resolutions, lists of deeds to and from C.V.L. Co., 1908 - 1911. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - “Chattanooga Southern R.R. (Tenn., Ala. & Georgis R.R., Successor)”. Letter from Col. Thomas Hubbard to A.D. Shepard re: Chattanooga Southern R.R. and Guatamala transaction., 10/6/13 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - “Chevy Chase Land Company”. Correspondence, Sept. - Dec. 1901. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - “Coal and Products Co.”. Two stock certificates owned by A.D. Shephard., 5/28/09 and 12/20/09 - (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - “Colorado Steam Navigation Co.”. (Two) stock certificates owned by F.S. Douty and owned by P.I. Co. - list of other certificates received, 4/24/1877, 11/10/93, 3/29/01. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - “Contract and Finance Co.”. Two notes to a `Black' from Lew Tashira, November, 1912. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - “Cosmos Club - J.E. Polhemus, Cancelled Checks - ”. List of members, some notations., April 1913 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - “Crocker-Huffman Land & Water Co.”. Copy of articles of incorporation contract with American Olive Co. and miscellaneous correspondence, (4/30, 1888), Sept. 1912 - Oct. 1935 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - “East Side Real Estate Co. of Portland, Ore.”. Transcript of entries from ledgers inclusive., 6-8 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - “El Verano Improvement Assn.”. Examples of stock cartificates list of concents include articles of incorporation notices of court action, annual meeting notices and proxies, resolutions, contracts, (1914, 1919), (6/13/08), (1912 - 1919). (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - “El Verano Villa Association”. Stock certificates (P.I. Co.), 1914, 1919. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - “Esquimalt & Nanaimo R.R. Co. & Wellington Collieries Co. Ltd.”. Articles of Assn., agreements re: sale of P.I. Co. Canadian interests in these two companies to James Dunsmuir, further agreements concerning sale and payment, lists of stock, correspondence, 3/26/02 - 4/11/1905 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - “Fresno Land & Improvement Co.”. Stock certificates (P.I. Co., George Crocker), 1892 - 1897. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - “Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio R.R.”. Correspondence with Franklin Trust Co., Jan. - Feb. 1910. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - “Garvey Bar Dredging Co. & Simmons Bar Dredging Co.”. Also Kalmath River Gold Mining Co. stock certificates, agreements, corporate description and reports, correspondence., Dates: 1910-1912. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean R.R. - 5s 21 sample bond”. Stock certificates and first mortgage bond, misc. other business include Polhemus resignation, trust agreement., (June 3, 1887) Oct. 1, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean Rwy. - Short Term investments Bank Deposit Book 1906-1924”. Correspondence from Crocker Nat'l. Bank re: investments., 1907-12 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean R.R.”. Correspondence from Brobeck, Phleger & Harrison, attnys. accompanying small checks as installment of 1/10 the principal of G.S.P. & O.R.R., (2/10/27 - 2/14/33). (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean R.R. Co.”. Agreements and correspondence concerning R.R. estate sales, 8/2/12 - 3/18/15. (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean R.R. - Fare Collections, ”. Ledger sheets., 9/28/07-2/28/08 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - “Geary St., Park & Ocean R.R. - Fare Collections, ”. Ledger sheets., 3/1/08-6/4/08 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - “Guatemala Central R.R. Co.”. Correspondence, financial reports, notices and minutes of G.C. R.R. & P.I. Co. Director's Meetings Completely owned by P.I. Co. - big money here., July 13, 1892 - July 5, 1934. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - “Guatemala, Mining Lands Report ”., 10/4/10 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - “Hotel Men's Confidential Agency”. Stock cortificate, Douty - Ishare., 3/10/1897. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - “Hotel Arcadia”. First mertgage bond, 10/25/1889. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - “Merced Fair Ground Association”. Stock certificate, P.I. Co. - 10 shares, 4/1/1895. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - “1901 Oil Co.”. List of stockholder and stock sales, stock certificates, minutes of meetings, some correspondence, notes -, dates: April, 1901 - August 1907. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - “North Beach & Mission Rwy. (Sold to Omnibus Cable Co., ”. Re: sale., 10/12/93) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - “Oak Creek Land & Lumber Co.”. Check book, cancelled checks, financial statement all from Crocker Nat'l. Bank, map of wells, stock certificates, Dept. of Interior documents, deed, correspondence. but some older documents included., Dates: basically 1908 - 1910 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - “Oakland, Brooklyn & Fruit Vale R.R.”. Stock certificates, P.I. Co. - 440 shares list of other shares held by P.I. Co. personnel., 2/12/89 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - “Oakland Railroad Company”. Stock certificates list of all shares held by P.I. Co. personnel., receipt of bonds, 7/25/87, 1901. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - “Occidental & Oriental S.S. (steamship) Co.”. Correspondence and lists re: stock. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - “Pacific & South Eastern Rwy.”. Articles of incorporation in Washington State, stock certificates, income tax forms, correspondence, dates: 4/24/08 - 4/11/22. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - “Pacific Cable Rwy. Co.”. Stock certificates list of other P.I. Co. shares., (8/30/04) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - “Pacific Construction Co.”. Promisory notes to P.I. Co., 11/17/1887 - 6/16/1888. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - “Pasadena Lake Vineyard Land & Water Co.”. List and correspondence re: stock., (2/25 -12/7/1895) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - “Portland & Willamette Valley Rwy. Co.”. Lists of stock owned by P.I. Co. and stock certificates., Dates: June 8, 1887 - Sept. 1900. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - “Portland and Yamhill R.R. Co.”. Lists of stock owned by P.I. Co. and certificates, Sept. 1892 - April 1893. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - “Sacramento Valley R.R. Co.”. Stock certificate correspondence, (Jan. 31, 1856), May, 1900. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - “San Gabriel Valley Rapid Transit Railway”. P.I. Co. owned stock certificates, Oct. - Nov. 1893. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - “San Joaquin Valley R.R. Co.”. Correspondence, promisory notes, stock certificates and lists. (C.P. & H.E. Huntington major force behind this line)., Dates: 4/22,1891 - 11/2,1892. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - “San Lorenzo Flume & Transportation”. List of stockholders certificates list of others signed over to P.I. Co., (11/1,1879), 7/1,1879 & 10/1,1883 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - “San Pedro Harbor, Dock & Land Assn.”. Stock certificates and list -, 10/9/93 - 3/20/01. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - “ `Soldiers” Additional Homestead Certificates' ”., 1896 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - “Sonoma Valley Improvement Co.”. Receipt (handwritten), promisory notes to P.I. Co., contracts for deeds, stocks certificates and lists, Dates: 5/16/1888 - 10/18/1907. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - “Sonoma Valley Land Co.”. Assignments of stock or interest to P.I. Co. or personnel of P.I. Co., stock certificates and list., Dates: Nov. - Dec. 1891. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - “Southern Development Co.”. Promisory notes to Thomas W. Pierce, ledger recording of notes, receipt upon payment. Stock certificates, August 30 - Nov. 1, 1864. Sept. 1, 1901 - July 23, 1902. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - “Standard Clay Co.”. Correspondence, stock transfer, 4/19/1912 - 7/7/1914. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - “St(eam)r, San Mateo”. Information on boat owned by P.I. Co., then correspondence, insurance claim and repair estimate re: encountor with ice near Alaska., Dates: May - Nov. 1909. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - “Str. `Santa Lucia' ”. Insurance policy for trip, 11/11/1895 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - “Toledo, St. Louis Western R.R.”. Letter re: stock, 2/23/21. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - “Union Fuel Co.”. Stock certificate and list, articles of incorporation in Calif., amended by-laws, notices of stockholder's meetings, 10/14/04 - Nov. 1907. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - “Union Fuel Co. - Voucher Record- (Plus Rocky Mtn. C. & I., 7/06-12/06)”. Bound ledger book (cf. Rocky Mountain Coal & Iron JL 17 - above)., 3/06-2/07 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - “Union Land & Oil Co. (Georgia) Memos and letter ”., July 8, 1896 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - “Universal Land Co.”. Notice of annual meeting, 5/1/35. (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - “Visalia City Bonds”. Correspondence, memos, notations., Dates: 1/23/1896 - 8/27/1900. (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - “Chart (Classification) of Accounts, Pacific Improvement Company”. Accounts undated explains nature but does not specify size of accounts., 1-63 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - “Special Report on the Liquidation of Pacific Improvement Company and Affiliated Companies, ”. Special report to Board of Directors., Oct. 31, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, ”. Financial report ot Board of Directors., Jan. 1924 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, March 1925”. Financial report to Board of Directors for months of, Jan., Feb. and March 1925. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, June 1925”. Financial report to Board of Directors for months, April, May, June 1925. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, March 1926”. Quarterly report of Board of Directors, for quarter, Jan. - March. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, June 1926”. Quarterly report ot Board of Directors April - (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Monthly Report, Sept. 1926”, Quarterly report to Board of Directors, July - Sept. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company, March 1927”. Quarterly report to Board of Directors, Jan. - March. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company, June 1927”. Quarterly report to Board of Directors, April - June. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company, Sept. 1927”. Quarterly report to Board of Directors, July - Sept. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1924 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1925 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1926 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1927 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1928 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - “Pacific Improvement Company Annual Report ”., 1929 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - “Annual Report Pacific Improvement Company ”., 1930 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - “Annual Report Pacific Improvement Company ”., 1932 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - “Annual Report Pacific Improvement Co. and Carbon Hill Coal Co. ”., 1933 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - “Chart (Classification) of Accounts, Castle Crags Report”. Undated accounts categorized as assets, liabilities, revenues, operating expenses or general expenses. Nature but not size of accounts specified. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - “Chart (Classification) of Accounts - Rancho Del Monte”. Same as above., 15-21 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - “Del Monte Properties Company Monthly Report, April 1924”. Financial report to Board of Directors, month of only. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - “Del Monte Properties Company monthly Report, ”. Financial report to Board of Directors, one month only., June 1926 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - “Report on Ione Coal and Iron Company, ”, Oct. 31, 1916. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - “Burned Books of Oil Co., Oak Creek L(and) & W(ater) Co., Sunset Seal Co.”., 1901 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - “Partially Burned Ledger Books, ”., 1901 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - “Castle Crags 1893 - 1918”. Leases, chattel mortgage, correspondence, maps and descriptions of land, release and conveyance of interest to P.I. Co., contracts for deeds., Dates: 7/1/1893 - 3/1/1918. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - “Castle Crags, Siskiyou & Shasta Counties 1920 - 1945”. Agreements, resolutions, quitclaim deed, financial statements and reports, correspondence, 1/8/20 - 6/27/45. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - “Castle Crag & McCloud River Auto Road Co.”. Reconnaissance map of Mt. Shasta area, toll card, articles of incorporation, notices and minutes of meeting (Stock-holders and Directors), agreements, stock certificates, correspondence, legal action takes in superior Court of Calif. by P.I. Co. against Castle Crag and McCloud River Co. - `Complaint' and `Order to show Cause and Restraining Order'., Dates: August 1906 - July 1919. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - “Parks, Annie W. - Uba Co. Property”. Personal, handwritten letter from Chas. F. Crocker to Mrs. Parks, (with typed copy), mortgage, bill of sale, satisfaction of mortgage, abstract of titles lease, release of mortgage., Aug. 21, 1891 (9/26/1888), Dates Range: 1888 - 1904. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - “San Francisco Lands - General”. Lists for tax purposes report by City Engineer on Sewer System for S.F. newspaper article re: City water system - also after, (undated), (1906), undated, 1906? (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - “San Francisco - Mission Blocks”. General lease, correspondence, mortgage, Julian Investment Co. - mortgage to P.I. Co., Insurance policy and correspondence., Dates: 7/13/06 - 7/31/13. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - “San Francisco Land - Paul Tract”. Receipts, promisory notes, release from mortgage, correspondence, City and County of S.F. Dept. of Public works report and map re: improvements, legal action, deed of trust., Dates: 4/6/08 - 11/24/20. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - “San Francisco Land - Potrero Dist., Kentucky, Illinois Streets - 19th - 24th”. Leases, agreements, sketched maps, deeds of trust, mortgages, correspondence, contracts., Dates 6/20/05 - 8/22/23. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - “San Francisco Land South St., Seventh St., Sixteenth St.”. Correspondence, memos and sketched maps, 1910 - 1911. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - “San Francisco Bay Islands - see also: P.I. Co. & Alta Livestock, P.I. Co. v. Pac. Hog Co.” Lease, statements of crushed rock extracted from islands, correspondence and accompanying statement, legal examination of abstract of title., Date: 6/5/06 - 6/11/15. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - “San Pedro Harbor, Los Angeles County”. Contract for deed, mortgages map and quitclaim deed (P.I. Co. to Southern Pacific), accompanying correspondence, (Aug. 1905 - June 1906), (Oct. - Nov. 1939). (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - “Santa Barbara - Abstract to Hope Ranch (Printed Edition - Wright Abstract Co.- ”., 6/22/09) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - “Santa Barbara - Certificates of Title, Various Parcels and Dates”. Certificates made deeds range in, 1919 - 1920, date 8/29,1885 - 4/12/13. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - “Hope and Ontare Ranches, Santa Barbara County”. Brochure, agreements, deeds of trust, receipt, city ordinance re: cost of water, schedule of release, summary of release schedule, subdivision maps of Hope Ranch Park, correspondence, literature and prospectus re: developing Hope Ranch as a club and resort., Dates: 8/20/10 - 11/24/28. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - “Laguna Blanca Water Co.”. Articles of incorporation, amended by-laws, notices and minutes of meetings (Stockholder's and Director's), Santa Barbara County Board of Supervisor's Proceedings re: Laguna Blanca Co. application, conveyance of deed, lease, list of property, tax statements., Dates: 10/26/1886 - 1911. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - “Laguna Blanca Water Co., Statements, ”. List of contents-1st item general statements of P.I. Co. and Laguna Blanca Water Co. with cover letters., 1904-1909 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - “Laguna Blanca Water Co. - Deeds”. 1st item is list of deeds included., Dates: 1/15/1887 - 12/31/17. (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Cf JL 16 - S.F.B. Morse and Del Monte Properties
  - “S.F.B. Morse Household Furnishings ”. Lists, inventories, correspondence with and bills from moving and freight companies, memos, receipts., 1918-1922 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - “S.F.B. Morse - Caves/Goodwin/Howard Land - Merced”. Receipts, deeds, mortgage, promisory notes, insurance policy, correspondence., Dates: 10/17/10 - 5/23/16. (Box 17, Folder 2)